这是二零二四年长沙市
初中学业水平考试英语
听力部分。
现在是听力试听时间。
Have you ever heard of Boxing Day?
The celebration happens in the United Kingdom and the countries that were once part
of the British Empire.
Boxing Day falls on the day after Christmas.
The official holiday dates back to 1871, yet no one is exactly sure how it started.
Some people think it has something to do with Christmas gifts.
In Britain, on the 26th of December,
the day after Christmas,
the very rich people in Victorian times gave gifts to their servants in small boxes.
That's why it was called Boxing Day.
Another possibility is that the name refers to money that was given to people in
need. Traditionally, a box was placed in churches to collect money.
The money from the box was given out to the poor on the day after Christmas.
No matter what Boxing Day's origins are, it's still a widely celebrated holiday.
For some, it is a big shopping day, and for others, it is a great day to eat, relax,
and watch sports.
Have you ever heard of Boxing Day?
The celebration happens in the United Kingdom and the countries that were once part
of the British Empire.
Boxing Day falls on the day after Christmas.
The official holiday dates back to 1871,
yet no one is exactly sure how it started.
Some people think it has something to do with Christmas gifts.
In Britain, on the 26th of December,
the day after Christmas,
the very rich people in Victorian times gave gifts to their servants in small boxes.
That's why it was called Boxing Day.
Another possibility is that the name refers to money that was given to people in
need. Traditionally, a box was placed in churches to collect money.
The money from the box was given out to the poor on the day after Christmas.
No matter what Boxing Day's origins are,
it's still a widely celebrated holiday.
For some, it is a big shopping day, and for others, it is a great day to eat, relax,
and watch sports.
奏听到此结束。
二零二四年长沙市初中学业水平考试
英语试卷第一部分听力测试
正式开始。
本部分分为第一。
第二两节。
做题时，请先将答案标在试题卷上。
本部分录音内容全部结束后，再将答案转涂到答题卡上。
听力材料以中速朗读两遍。
第一节。
听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的
the A, B, and 1.
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后。
你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话读两遍。
John, what do you want to be when you grow up?
I want to be a scientist.
2. Frank, what is your hobby?
I like playing chess.
3. There will be a kite festival on April the 17th.
Yes, I can't wait to see all kinds of flying
4. Welcome Welcome Welcome Changsha.
4. Welcome to Changsha.
Did you have a good time on the train?
Yeah, pretty good.
Welcome to Changsha.
Did you have a good time on the train?
Yeah, pretty good.
5. What would you like to drink today, coffee or tea?
Neither. Just give me a glass of please.
What would you like to drink today, coffee or tea?
第二节：听下面六段对话或独白。
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的
B, and read each question.
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话。
或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听第六段才。
After dialogue or read
have All well, Not so good.
I'm just feeling worried about writing this report.
Are you almost done with it?
Far from it.
And I will make a presentation in class tomorrow.
All well, Betty?
Not so good.
I'm just feeling worried about writing this report.
Are you almost done with it?
Far from it.
And I will make a presentation in class tomorrow.
听第七段材料。
and answer the eighth and ninth questions.
moved there two weeks ago.
How's your neighborhood?
It's quiet, especially in the evening.
That's nice. I want to move to somewhere quiet, too.
My neighborhood is too noisy.
Lily, I heard you moved to a new town.
Yes, I moved there two weeks ago.
How's your neighborhood?
It's quiet, especially in the evening.
That's nice. I want to move to somewhere quiet, too.
My neighborhood is too noisy.
听第八段材料，回答第十、十一题。
looking for a stamp, Alice.
A stamp? What do you want a stamp for?
I've written a letter to Uncle Bob, and I want to post the letter before noon.
Why don't you just email him?
Bob is going to have a party for his 80th birthday on Saturday afternoon.
He will be happy to get a real letter.
Why are you everything out of your box?
I'm looking for a stamp, Alice.
stamp? What do you want a stamp for?
I've written a letter to Uncle Bob, and I want to post the letter before noon.
Why don't you just email him?
Bob is going to have a party for his 80th birthday on Saturday afternoon.
He will be happy to get a real letter.
听第九段材料，回答第十二至十四题。
I hate waiting rooms in the hospital, don't you?
Yes, I get so bored sitting here waiting for other patients to be seen.
Wait, do I know you?
Yes, think back to Johnson Primary School.
Jack Thomas, we were in the same class.
You know, you've certainly changed.
So have you, Emily.
For the better, I should add.
Thank you. How long has it been since we last met?
Thirteen years? No, it has been fifteen years.
Oh, that's long That's long time.
That's That's a long time.
That's a long time.
a That's a That's That's
That's That's a long time.
That's a long That's a That's a long time.
听第十段材料，回答第十五至十七题。
That's No, I am busy preparing my paper these days.
For this paper, I have done a survey among one hundred students.
What is your survey about?
It is about students'
favorite sports. What are the results?
Most of the students said ping -pong.
Some few said basketball.
When are you supposed to hand in the paper?
Tomorrow. By the way, what are you working on, Beth?
A reading project.
It's so hard.
I really need to take a walk to relax myself.
Tim, are you going for a walk this evening?
No, I am busy preparing my paper these days.
For this paper, I have done a survey among one hundred students.
What is your survey about?
It is about students'
favorite sports. What are the results?
Most of the students said ping -pong.
Some few said basketball.
When are you supposed to hand in the paper?
Tomorrow. By the way, what are you working on, Beth?
A reading project.
It's so hard.
I really need to take a walk to relax myself.
is survey What the
听第十一段材料，回答。
把第十八至二十题。
Well, I have always loved to travel.
I still remember the first place I visited was Africa, where there was no running
water or toilet, but it did not matter to me.
In Africa, I was really excited when I saw animals running freely in the wild.
Since my visit to Africa, I have visited many other places,
Australia, China, and America, and I plan to visit Russia next year.
People often ask me why I love to travel.
How could anyone not love traveling?
There is always such a wonderful place that I can see new things, learn new
languages, and taste new foods.
However, it's expensive to travel.
There are so many costs of traveling.
I have to pay for the hotel,
food, and some other things.
Anyway, I really love to travel.
Well, I have always loved to travel.
I still remember the first place I visited was Africa, where there was no running
water or toilet, but it did not matter to me.
In Africa, I was really excited when I saw animals running freely in the wild.
Since my visit to Africa, I have visited many other places, Australia, China, and
America, and I plan to visit Russia next year.
People often ask me why I love to travel.
How could anyone not love traveling?
There is always such a wonderful place that I can see new things, learn new
languages, and taste new foods.
However, it's expensive to travel.
There are so many costs of traveling.
I have to pay for the hotel, food, and some other things.
Anyway, I really love to travel.
听力测试到此结束，请将试题卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。